<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Desk Reject</title>
    <link>http://deskreject.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Desk Reject</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://deskreject.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>W.W.P.M.D.?</title>
      <link>http://deskreject.com/2017/06/w.w.p.m.d./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deskreject.com/2017/06/w.w.p.m.d./</guid>
      <description>One of the most contentious issues in recent debates about replication studies concerns the importance of context in explaining failed replications. Those who question the value of direct replication often suggest that many psychological effects should be expected not to replicate because they depend so strongly on a multitude of seemingly inconsequential contextual factors. Thus, because you can’t step in the same river twice, direct replication attempts should often be expected to fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rules of Replication: Part II</title>
      <link>http://deskreject.com/2017/05/the-rules-of-replication-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deskreject.com/2017/05/the-rules-of-replication-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Cece doesn’t understand the rules of the couch.  Do replication studies need special rules? In my previous post I focused on the question of whether replicators need to work with original authors when conducting their replication studies. I argued that this rule is based on the problematic idea that original authors somehow own an effect and that their reputations will be harmed if that effect turns out to be fragile or to have been a false positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rules of Replication</title>
      <link>http://deskreject.com/2017/05/the-rules-of-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deskreject.com/2017/05/the-rules-of-replication/</guid>
      <description>Recently I traveled to Vienna for APS’s International Convention on Psychological Science, where I gave a talk on “The Rules of Replication.” Thanks to the other great talks in the session, it was well attended. But as anyone who goes to academic conferences knows, “well attended” typically means that at best, there may have been a couple hundred people in the room. And it seems like kind of a waste to prepare a talk—one that I will probably only give once—for such a limited audience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>