<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Measurement on The Desk Reject</title>
    <link>https://deskreject.com/tags/measurement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Measurement on The Desk Reject</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://deskreject.com/tags/measurement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Happiness Is Harder (But Maybe Also Easier) Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://deskreject.com/2019/03/measuring-happiness-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deskreject.com/2019/03/measuring-happiness-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: Experiential measures of subjective well-being solve, in a clear and obvious way, one possible threat to validity that affects global self-reports. The obviousness of this advantage, however, sometimes leads people to overlook the fact that experiential measures may have their own unique threats to validity. Specifically, the fact that experiential measures require respondents to repeatedly answer the same questions over and over again may pull for responses that deviate from what the researcher expects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Measure Happiness</title>
      <link>https://deskreject.com/2019/02/how-to-measure-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deskreject.com/2019/02/how-to-measure-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who has ever taught Intro Psych knows that one of the most popular lectures is the one that covers visual illusions. It’s easy to understand why. Illusions like the famous Müller-Lyer illusion shown below provide a clear example of times when our perception of the world is clearly, and demonstrably wrong. Although it’s almost impossible not to see the three lines as differing in length, simply removing the arrows at the ends shows that they are all, in fact, the same.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>